Date Tech              Karasuno
(東峰)((はぁはぁ
(東峰･ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)＜強靱な壁に
惨敗してから３か月＞
Three months have passed since they thrashed us with their Iron Wall.
(日向翔陽)((ブロクが
目の前からいなくなて
The blockers vanish from my sight,
and I get a clear view of the other side of the net.
ネトの向こう側が
ばあと見えるんです))
(東峰)＜そんな場面も
今まであたはずなんだけど＞
I must've seen it somewhere along the line,
but I just couldn't picture what it looked like past the Iron Wall anymore.
＜どうしても鉄壁の向こう側は
イメジできなくなていた＞
＜鉄壁の向こう側は
どんな景色だろうか＞
I wonder what the view looks like on the other side of the Iron Wall.
Rolling...
(西谷)ロリング
(東峰)あ
(西谷)サンダアゲイン
Thunder...
Again!
よしゃ
心配することなんかなんもねぇ
All right! We've got nothing to worry about!
(一同)あ
(西谷)みんな前だけ見てけよ
You guys focus on what's in front!
I've got your backs.
背中は俺が守てやるぜ
(３人)カカコいい
Th...
That's so cool!
Fly
The Iron Wall of Date
(澤村･茂庭)整列
Fly
The Iron Wall of Date
Form a line!
Fly
The Iron Wall of Date
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
(部員)ゴゴレツゴ
レツゴ伊達工
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
Episode Seventeen:
The Iron Wall
(伊達工応援団)ｺﾞｰｺﾞｰﾚｯﾂｺﾞｰ
(追分)お前たちよく聞け
The Iron Wall of Date
All of you, listen up!
烏野の速攻には確かに驚いた
Karasuno's fast attack definitely took us by surprise!
But that's only due to the height of the spiker!
だがそれは
あの身長だたからだ
あのバネはすさまじいが
やてるのは普通の速攻だ
He may have an incredible vertical, but that's a normal fast attack!
見た目に惑わされるなよ
Don't let your eyes fool you.
向こうのエスと同様に
徹底的に止めろ
Completely prevent him from scoring, just as you did with their ace!
もう一度見せてやれ
お前たちの鉄壁を
Show it to them one more time.
Show them your Iron Wall!
Yessir!
(繋心)１回戦見た感じだと
After watching them in the first round,
一発目は
強烈なサブが来るはずだ
I expect their first shot will be a powerful serve.
サブで崩して
確実にブロクでしとめて
They crush with serves and block every point.
Date Tech starts by discouraging their opponents from the get-go.
出ばなをくじくていうのが
伊達工の立ち上がりのﾊﾟﾀｰﾝぽい
Receive the first ball and get it up in the air!
１本目
レシブしかり上げてけよ
Yessir!
So, you know what to do, Kageyama?
で分かてんな影山
(影山飛雄)はい
Yes, sir.
よし鉄壁を切り崩してやれ
Good.
Now break through that Iron Wall!
Yessir!
(澤村)烏野ファイ
Karasuno, fight!
Yeah!
(溝口)あれ烏野のエスは
That's funny. Karasuno's ace is starting in the back row.
後衛スタトですか
Yeah. They're starting in the strongest receiving formation.
(入畑)うむいちばん
ﾚｼｰﾌﾞ力のあるフォメシｮンで
スタトだな
伊達工は１回戦と変わらずだな
Date Tech is playing it the same as the first round.
≪頑張れ≫
You can do it!
(西谷)さ来い
(田中)一本
Bring it!
One point!
Kamasaki, you can do it!
(茂庭)鎌先ナイサ
(笹谷)ナイサ
C'mon!
大地さん
おう
Daichi!
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
≪きれいなフォムだ≫
He has a clean form.
It's difficult to read how high the set will be.
≪トスがどこに上がるのか
簡単に読めないが
However...
ぐ
ピ
(田中)よしゃ
ナイスコス日向
Right on! Nice placement, Hinata!
(武田)
ああ向こうのブロク
Here I thought their blockers were one step behind!
一歩出遅れたと
思たんですけどねぇ
あれがリドブロクですか
Is that "read blocking"?
The type where you jump after seeing the set?
トスを見てから跳ぶていう
(繋心)おう
Yeah.
今までの対戦校はトスを
ある程度予測してから跳ぶ
Until now, most opposing schools used "commit blocks," where they jump after predicting the set to a degree.
コミトブロクが多かたが
But Date Tech uses hardcore read blocking.
伊達工は
徹底したリドブロク
トスがどこに上がるのかを
見てから跳ぶんだ
They jump after they see where the set is going.
つまり
In other words...
囮にはなかなか
引掛かてくれないつうことだ
they don't fall for decoys that easily.
その分ブロクに
一歩出遅れるんだが
This sets them a step behind making the block,
but their number seven narrows that gap instantly.
あの７番
それを一気に詰めてきやがる
He's big, and he's fast.
でかいうえに速ぇ
(武田)こ怖いですね
That's scary.
あのリドブロクには
手を焼きそうです
Their read blocking is going to be trouble.
烏野はどうしますかね
(入畑)さて
How do you think Karasuno will deal with it?
I'm not sure.
Karasuno hasn't used their big guns in this tournament yet.
烏野もこの大会でまだ
あの切り札を見せてないからな
Karasuno             Date Tech
(澤村)影山ナイサ
ナイサ一本
Kageyama, give us a nice serve!
Take it for a point!
≪ち
リベロんとこ打ちまた
Shit!
I sent it straight to their libero!
相変わらず強烈なサブだ
That's one powerful serve.
He'll be scary to face once he learns to control it.
あれでコントロルが
身についたら怖いねぇ
く
うお拾た
すげぇ
Whoa, he dug it out!
Holy crap!
龍すまんカバ
(田中)よしゃ
Sorry, Ryuu! Cover it!
Got it!
バク
≪バクアタク
Back!
A back attack?!
There were practically none in the previous match.
≪前回の試合では
ほとんどなかたはず≫
旭さん
Asahi!
Shit!
くそ
(武田)ああ
Aw...
There was nothing you could do! Put it behind you!
(繋心)しょうがねぇしょうがねぇ
切り替えろ
旭さんすんません
次は拾います
Asahi, I'm sorry!
I'll get the next one!
おう頼むでも次は決める
Sure. Thanks.
But I'll make the next one count!
(二口)あれ
なんだよもと心折れろよ
Huh? Aw, come on. Would it kill you to be more dejected?
(茂庭)性格悪いこと言うな二口
痛
Stop talking like a thug, Futakuchi!
Ow!
Karasuno             Date Tech
ち
ピ
Damn!
Huh?
(烏野一同)よしゃ
タチネト
All right!
Net touch.
We lucked out!
いいから気にすんなて
Just don't let it get to you!
今の伊達工の
タチネトか
Date Tech just touched the net?
烏野は命拾いしましたね
Karasuno avoided disaster.
しかしすごいねぇ
They're pretty good, though.
The bond between their fast attacks and blocks is tight.
速い攻撃にもブロクが
しかり２枚はひついてる
こいつは手ごわいねぇ
They're gonna be tough.
ピ
(茂庭)ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
Futakuchi!
二口
I'm open!
(東峰)オプン
(澤村)旭
Asahi!
ピ
(東峰)あ
Right on!
あアウト
こちの得点ですか
What, is it out? We get the point?
Nice job, Azumane!
ナイスだ東峰
Karasuno             Date Tech
(溝口)点数的には
烏野が一歩リドしてますが
Karasuno is barely maintaining their lead.
辛うじてシャトアウトを
免れている感じで
But they're being thwarted just enough to
prevent them from making satisfying spikes.
気持ちよくは
打たせてもらえませんね
うむ今
ギリギリ逃れているブロクに
Yes.
If the blocks they're narrowly avoiding start to catch up to them multiple times in a row,
連続で捕まり始めれば
流れを一気に持ていかれる
Nice receive!
the momentum will be taken from them.
Futakuchi!
(茂庭)二口
(田中)ナイスワンタチ日向
Nice job getting a hand on it, Hinata!
No way!
マジか
チャンスボル
Here's our chance to score!
(追分)
相手が取るはずだた１点を
We take the point that was nearly theirs and make it ours in a split-second.
一瞬で自分たちの１点にする
相手の心を折り
同時に味方の士気を高める
We break their spirits while simultaneously boosting our own morale.
最強の防御で最速の攻撃
It is both the strongest defense and the fastest attack.
That...
それが
(追分)ブロク
is the block.
ピ
(伊達工応援団)わあ
The Iron Wall of Date
(小原)ナイスブロク
ナイスだ青根
Nice block!
Nice one, Aone!
パチン
ぐわ
Way to go, way to go, Aone!
高く速く更には広い壁
It's a faster, wider, higher wall.
Good, good! Very good! Good, good!
まさに
There's no doubt.
鉄壁か
It's an Iron Wall.
Shit!
Don't fret it. Focus on the next one.
気にすんな次だ次
ん
Huh?
次は絶対に決まる
We'll definitely score next time.
絶対あ
We will?
Oh! Wanna go for it?
やんのか
ギュンの方やんのか
ls it time to do the zoom?!
ははは
えらい久々な気ぃすんな
It feels like it's been ages.
I want you to use your fastest speed and best jump.
お前のいちばんのジャンプ
いちばんのスピドで跳べ
ボルは俺が
I'll bring the ball
持ていく
to you.
Haikyuu !!
≪烏野の最速の攻撃は
おそらくあの１０番
Karasuno's fastest attack will come from their number ten.
しかし
その速攻はこちらの壁の範囲内≫
However, their fast attack will be within the perimeter of our wall.
≪なのにどうして
全く焦ていないんだ
So why aren't they acting the least bit flustered?
駒と戦たとき
Do you know why our deviant fast attack
was foiled when we played against Nekoma?
変人速攻は
どうして止められたと思う
((はい
犬岡がすごかたから
Yes, sir! Because Inuoka was crazy impressive!
((ああまあ
それは大前提だけどもな
Uh.
Yeah, I suppose that's a good point.
駒のミドルブロカが
日向の動きに慣れたから))
Because Nekoma's middle blocker
became accustomed to Hinata's moves.
駒に関しては
Yup. Familiarization.
Although in Nekoma's case, I believe
they had a real sharp player on the team.
相当頭の切れるヤツが
いたんだと思うおそらく
I suspect that player was Mr. Pudding-head.
あのプリン頭だ))
((研磨か
It was Kenma!
(孤爪)((へぶしゅ
(犬岡)((研磨さんが風邪ひいた
Kenma caught a cold!
Inuoka, shut up. I didn't.
(孤爪)
((犬岡うるさいひいてない))
To be honest, I didn't expect them to
come up with a countermeasure that fast,
((正直あんなに早く対策を
立ててくるとは思わなかたが
どんなチムでも遅かれ早かれ
but sooner or later, every team will become accustomed to the deviant fast attack and learn to keep up with it.
変人速攻に慣れて
ある程度ついてくるようになる
お前らの速攻は
相当強力な武器だが
Your fast attack is quite a powerful weapon,
but it isn't invincible.
無敵てわけじゃない
重要なのは
The most important thing is...
≪使いどころ≫
...how we use it.
Karasuno             Date Tech
龍
よしゃ
Ryuu!
Got it!
≪どんなに神経とがらしても
リドブロクじゃ
Even the most finely tuned read blocking can't keep up with this!
追いつけねぇよ
(観客たち)うお
(観客)なんだ今の
What was that?!
Yeah!
よしゃ
し
Yes!
They used their monster fast attack.
(岩泉)出たよ化け物速攻
(溝口)やぱ強烈ですね
It sure is intense.
Wow, that's scary. It's obscene.
(入畑)怖いねぇ嫌だねぇ
(及川)ほんと天才むかつくわ
Prodigies really piss me off.
(コチ)なんてムチャなトス
What a ridiculous set.
Did he make that hard set just to shake off Aone?
青根を力ずくで振り切るために
あんな乱暴なトスを
It couldn't be that simple. The spiker hit it too well.
それにしてはスパイカが
ちゃんと打てていた
But that had to be a fluke.
でもあんなトス
たまたま打てたとしか
Do you know who he is?
あの１０番何者か知てるか
Their number ten.
(コチ)いえ中学の大会でも
全く見覚えはないですね
No. I don't recall him from the
junior high tournament whatsoever.
≪まぐれか意図的か
Was it a fluke, or was it deliberate?
Tsukishima, we're counting on you.
月島頼んだぞ
(月島)はい
Sure.
王様ネトから
ちょい離したトス頼むね
Your Highness, I'd like a set further back from the net.
I don't want to be caught up by blockers.
ブロクに捕まりたくないから
んぬん
はあ
Hmph.
What was that?
I said fine!
分かたつてんだよ
いや明らかに言てなかたよね
No, you obviously didn't.
庶民には指図されたくないですか
そうですか
So you don't like being ordered by plebeians. I see how it is!
Huh?!
ああ
(田中)げ
Guys, knock it off!
お前らやめろ学習しねぇな
You never learn!
Kageyama finally used his fast attack.
影山やと使いましたね
あの速攻
伊達工は混乱してるだろうな
I'll bet Date Tech is confused.
You'll never find another fast attack like it in the world.
あんな速攻世界中探したて
見られるもんじゃないからな
ピ
(入畑)またく末恐ろしい
I'm terrified of what they might become.
あすみませんすみません
ボケェ
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Dumbass! Hinata, you klutzy piece of shit!
ほかはいろいろと
発展途上なんだけどな
Everything else is a learning curve.
Shake it off.
Noya, I'm sorry.
ノヤさんすみません
任せろ
I've got this!
Karasuno             Date Tech
ピ
(茂庭)青根ナイサ
Aone, give us a good one!
ピ
(烏野一同)よしゃ
今度は普通のトスだたな
All right!
That was a normal set.
Was the last one a fluke?
さきのはまぐれかそれとも
１０番しか使えないのか
Or is number ten the only one who can do it?
(作並)お疲れす
Good job!
Nice, Tsukishima! One more!
ナイス月島もう一本
(山口)ツキナイス
Tsukki, nice one!
Hey!
(鎌先)おらぁ
ピ
よし取られたら取り返す
All right! Let's take back what was ours!
(茂庭)ナイス鎌先
(笹谷)鎌ちさすが
Nice, Kamasaki!
Kamacchi, you're awesome!
Let's take it back!
取り返すぞ
しゃあ
Yeah!
Karasuno                Date Tech
Karasuno              Date Tech
点差動きませんね
でも今のロテションで
The point gap is static.
But in the current rotation, Karasuno's
number ten has come to the front row again.
烏野の１０番が
また前衛に上がてきたな
来たか１０番
あのやたら速いトス
Number ten is here.
Kageyama hasn't made any of those way-too-fast sets since.
さきの一本きり
上げませんね影山は
That's right! When I saw his
Kitagawa First match in junior high,
そういえば中学の
北川第一の試合を見たとき
さきみたいなトスで
ｽﾊﾟｲｶｰを置き去りていう場面を
I seem to recall him leaving the spiker in the lurch several times with sets like that last one.
何度か見た覚えがありますね
確かに
さきのトスを見た瞬間
You're right. The moment I saw that set, I was sure
that his old bad habit had reared its ugly head again.
中学時代の
悪癖が出たのだと思た
But their number ten hit that thing.
でもあの１０番は打ていた
(追分)さも当然のように
Almost like he was meant to.
(茂庭)二口
Futakuchi!
ピ
(鎌先)ナイス二口
Karasuno             Date Tech
Nice, Futakuchi!
伊達工も離されないな
Date Tech is tenacious.
Hey, it looks like Karasuno's
number ten has rotated to the front row.
お烏野の１０番が
前衛に来たと思たら今度は
Date Tech's amazing blocker, number seven, also has his turn in the front row.
伊達工のブロクすげぇ７番も
前衛のタンだ
鉄壁ｖｓ超速攻
It's Iron Wall versus Super-Fast Attack.
≪さきの変人速攻一発じゃ
まだまぐれと思われてるかもな≫
They might be thinking that last deviant fast attack was a fluke.
もう一発行くぞ
おう
We're going in for another one!
Right!
(澤村)ネトイン前前
It's on our side! Forward!
拾たけど
He retrieved it!
But they can't possibly do a fast attack with that positioning.
あそこから速攻は無理かな
誰に上げ
Who will he give it—
ピ
よしゃ
またあのトス
Right on!
Nice job, Hinata, Kageyama!
It's that set again!
Thank you, sir!
Okay! We're going in!
しかも今度はあんなに
ネトから離れた位置から
And this time he did it far back from the net!
まぐれじゃないのか
That isn't a fluke?
(烏野一同)よしゃ
伊達工たまらずタイムアウトか
Right on!
Date Tech immediately called for a timeout.
Karasuno's number ten is incredible.
烏野の１０番すげぇな
あんなトス打てねぇだろ普通
You just can't hit a set like that normally.
(岩泉)技術的にすげぇのは
ｽﾊﾟｲｶｰに完璧にトス合わせてる
The setter who aligns the set so perfectly
for the spiker is more amazing, technically.
セタの方なんだよな
(及川)け
Heh!
(花巻)あんな神業
初見じゃ分かんないでしょ
It's like watching God perform a miracle.
We couldn't figure it out at first either.
俺らも最初分かんなかたし
Karasuno             Date Tech
If that fast attack is the real deal,
we can't keep up with it using read blocking.
(追分)あの速攻が本物なら
リドブロクでは
追いつけそうもない
But ignoring it would be like taking a beating with the gloves down.
かといて放置すれば無抵抗で
殴られ続けるようなものだ
１０番からの攻撃の可能性が
あるときだけは
Any time there's the possibility of an attack by number ten, don't mark the set. Mark him.
トスじゃなく
１０番自体をマクする
トスはある程度予測して跳べ
Predict the set and jump.
However, keep in mind that
the attack may've been a fluke.
ただあの攻撃が
まぐれだた可能性もある
Keep cool and play it by ear.
慌てずに臨機応変に行くぞ
(一同)はい
Yes, sir!
I've never seen a fast attack like that before.
(笹谷)あんな速攻初めて見たな
Do you think their number ten
is the only one who can do that?
(茂庭)あの速攻は
１０番だけが使えんのかな
つうかあれまぐれじゃ
ないとしたら化け物だろ
You know, if that isn't a fluke, that means they're monsters.
確かに
あの速攻にはビビたけど
That fast attack was freakish,
but the normal fast attacks they've been using
from the start can sneak by if we're not careful.
最初から使てる普通の速攻だて
気ぃ抜いたらかわされんぞ
Anyway, we just need to stop number ten.
まあとりあえず
１０番を止めればいいて話で
(鎌先)
おめぇはいちいち軽いんだよ
You're way too easygoing.
(二口)重いよりは
いいじゃないすか
It's better than being uptight.
That's why you don't get the chicks.
そんなんじゃモテないすよ
(鎌先)なんだとてめぇ
What did you just say?!
But it's true.
(茂庭)止めろ青根
(鎌先)この野郎
Stop them, Aone!
Why, you!
(青根)ふん
(二口･鎌先)ぬわ
In retrospect, all they've gotta do is stop number ten, right?
でもさ逆に言えば１０番さえ
止めちゃえばいいんだよな
ん
目立てんのあの10番だけだし
He's the only one standing out.
ほかは伊達工のブロクの方が
勝てる感じだし
Date Tech's block seems to be beating the rest.
That's true.
確かにな
Anyway, we're going to stop their number ten!
とにかくあの１０番を止めるぞ
(一同)うす
Yessir!
≪１０番を止めなければ
１０番を≫
We need to stop number ten.
Number ten.
(２人)≪１０番を≫
The Iron Wall of Date
Number ten.
(伊達工応援団)≪１０番を≫
(場内一同)≪１０番を≫
Number ten!
(繋心)((とにかく
Anyway,
あのちこい１０番
すげぇ的な空気を作る))
"that tiny number ten" will set an excellent mood.
((それが
大きくなればなるほど
The brighter the mood is...
さあ来い
Now, bring it!
...and the more Hinata shines,
(繋心)((日向が光れば光るほど
相手のブロクは目がくらむのさ))
the more it will blind the opponent blockers.
(嶋田)遅ぇよ
試合終わてたらどうすんだよ
You're so slow! We could've missed the match!
(滝ノ上)だて
珍しくお客が来てて
But customers are so rare!
Hurry up!
≫(道宮)早く早く
(２人)ん
(道宮)よかた
男子の２回戦まだやてる
Great! The boys are still playing their second round match.
I don't believe it! They're beating Date Tech!
(アヤ)
すごい伊達工に勝てる
来いや
(３人)え
Bring it on!
ピ
All right!
くそ速ぇな
けど惜しいじゃん青根
He's ridiculously fast.
But that was close, Aone!
(道宮)え何今の
(烏野女子)速攻
What was that?
A fast attack?
(烏野女子)
あれて１年生だよね
He's a first-year, isn't he?
Did that little guy just jump incredibly high?
(アヤ)あの小さい子
すごい跳ばなかた
ぬふふ
(嶋田)お前がドヤ顔すんなよ
Don't look so smug.
(菅原)いいぞ日向
あれ
Looking good, Hinata!
What the?
(菅原)その調子だもう一本
That's the way! Do another one!
(山口)ナイサ一本
(道宮)菅原は出てないのか
Make it a good serve!
Sugawara isn't playing.
ピ
(東峰)西谷
Nishinoya!
Ｂ
トスくれ
B!
Give me a set!
(二口)≪攻撃は２枚≫
(茂庭)≪どちだ
Two attackers! Who will it be?!
≪跳ぶ
He's jumping!
≪あ跳ばない
He's not jumping!
く
Yes!
(アヤ)今度は普通の速攻
Now a normal fast attack?
(烏野女子)トスの速さを
使い分けてるてこと
So are they setting at different speeds for each scenario?
(澤村)((実は結構
面白い１年が入てきてさぁ
The thing is, some pretty interesting first-years joined us recently.
((あいつらが機能すれば烏野は
If they prove effective,
I think Karasuno can improve by leaps and bounds.
爆発的に進化するんじゃないかて
思うんだよね))
すごい
Incredible.
(笹谷)
くそ何なんだあの１０番
Shit. Who is their number ten?
Okay, listen up!
Don't get sucked in!
のまれないこちの攻撃だて
ちゃんと決まてる
We're making our attacks count too!
確かにあの１０番には
びくりしたけど
Yes, their number ten took us by surprise,
but you guys have overpowered all kinds of spikers!
お前たちは今までいろんな
スパイカをねじ伏せてきた
Including Karasuno's ace!
烏野のエスもだ
And we'll stop them again!
今回だて止めてやろう
(一同)はい
Yes, sir!
Please say "we" instead of "you guys."
｢お前たち｣じゃなくて
｢俺たち｣て言てくださいよ
二口今までクソ生意気な
後輩と思ててごめん
Futakuchi, I'm sorry I thought you were a snotty underclassman all this time.
思てたんですか
ピ
Is that what you thought?
(青根)ふん
く
(伊達工応援団)わあ
(部員)ナイスキ青根
The Iron Wall of Date
Nice job, Aone!
うわぁ２回跳んだ
あんなに大きいと
He jumped twice!
When you're that big, the smallest jump can put your hand over the net.
少しのジャンプでもネトから
手が出てしまうんですねぇ
(繋心)身長に加えて腕の長さと
肩幅の広さも強力な武器だ
Not only is he tall, his long arms and
wide shoulders make powerful weapons.
でもそれだけじゃない
But there's more to him.
視野の狭くならない冷静さと
He's too calm to get tunnel vision,
and he has the tenacity to stop the ball.
絶対に止めるという執念
両方を併せ持ているからこその
ブロクだ
His block comes from the combination of the two.
おいおいブロクやべぇな
Hey, hey. That block is scary.
ああいうブロクは
流れを呼び込むからな
A block like that can change the momentum.
They need to make the next point, or Date Tech will ride the wave.
次の一本できちり切らねぇと
伊達工が波に乗ちまうぞ
(茂庭)もう一本止めるぞ
(一同)おお
We're going to stop another one!
Yeah!
Keep your cool!
(山口)落ち着いて切てこ
(菅原)一本
Stop them here!
Karasuno             Date Tech
ピ
(茂庭)二口思い切り行けよ
Futakuchi! Give it what you've got!
(澤村)すまんカバ
(西谷)龍
Sorry, cover it!
Ryuu!
(田中)オライ
センタ
Got it!
Center!
Hinata!
日向
はい
On it!
(西谷)しゃあ
西谷
All right!
Nishinoya!
Kageyama!
(西谷)影山
はい
Right!
Karasuno has three attackers in the front!
≪烏野は前衛３枚誰が来る
Which will it be?!
持てこい
Send it my way!
１０番
Number ten!
≪エスの前の道を切り開く
Blaze a path...
for the ace!
((ネトの向こう側が
I get a clear view
ばあと
of the other side.
≪ああそうだ
Yes, I remember now.
≪これだ≫
This is it!
(２人)よ
よしゃ
Y—
Yes!
(３人)きゃあ
あれは
That's the same pipe Nekoma did!
音駒がやてたパイプ
(田中･西谷)旭さん
(澤村)旭
Asahi!
You guys are amazing.
(東峰)お前らすごいよ
ありがとうな
I appreciate it.
Hey, you're the one who made it count!
(西谷)何言てんすか
(山口)ナイス旭さん
Nice, Asahi!
(西谷)決めたの旭さんでしょ
堂々としてほら
Hold your head up high!
(菅原)((エスの前の道も
切り開いてくれ))
I want you to blaze a path for our ace!
Yes!
し
ああどうした
What's wrong?
今決めたの俺じゃないのに
I'm not the one who scored that point.
俺スパイク打てないのに
I'm not the one who spiked that, but...
((１０番
Number ten!
すごいぞくぞくした
It really gave me chills.
最強の囮も
エスに劣らずカコいいだろ
See? Being the greatest decoy
is just as cool as being the ace.
最強の囮
The greatest...
decoy.
Okay, we've showed them every weapon in our arsenal.
さあこちの手持ちの武器は
これで全部さらした
(繋心)こからが正念場だぞ
Now it's do-or-die.
Next Episode Preview
It's not like before.
(青根)前と違う
(二口)何がだ青根
What's not, Aone?
(青根)烏野
(二口)だな
Karasuno.
For sure! Now that the setter and short guy are on the team, it's hard to target our block—
あのセタとチビちゃんが
入たことで
ブロクの的が絞りづらく
(青根)女子マネジャの髪型
The lady manager's hair style.
You're hung up on that?!
(二口)そこかよ
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Eighteen:
Back Protection
"Back Protection."
昨日の夜､長崎県佐世保市で
高校１年生の同級生の女子生徒を
殺害したとして､
１５歳の女子生徒が殺人の疑いで
逮捕された
女子生徒は同級生を殺害した後､